Guide to the Joseph R. Starobin and Robert S. Starobin Papers, 1945-1976
Department of Special Collections
- Series II: Robert Starobin
  - Subseries IV: Robert Starobin's Radical Newspapers
    - Free Student - May 2 Movement Student News (NY) nos. 2-4 (1970) (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Freedom News (SF) IV:11 (Nov. 1970) (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Good Times (San Francisco) III:28 (17 July 1970) (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Guardian, independent radical newsweekly (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - 1969:May 17, June 28, July 12, Sept. 6, 20, 27, Oct. 4, 11, 18, 25, Nov. 1, 15, 22, 29, Dec. 6, 13
        1970: Jan. 31, Feb. 14, 19, 21, 28, Mar. 7, 14, 21, Apr. 4, 18, 20, 25, May 2, 9, 23, June 13, 20.
      - 18 April - published clandestinely after office attacked
      - 13 June -, 2 copies
    - Harbinger (Toronto) II:7 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Kaleidoscope (Madison, WI) I:2-4, II:10 (July 1969-May 1970) (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Kensington Peoples Press (Phila.) I:1 (Nov. 1970) (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Leviathan (San Francisco) -spectacular graphics I:7 (Dec. 69) (Box 30, Folder 20)
      - I:8 (Feb 70)
      - I:9 (Mar. 70)
      - II:1 (May 70
      - II:2 (June 70)
      - II:3 (Summer 70)
      - II:1 (May 70)- "Women Unite", (4copies)
      - II:2 (June 70)- "The Reactionaries are more and more alarmed..."
      - II:3 (Summer 70) "Cuba for beginners", (2 copies)
    - Liberal (Toronto) I:3 (Sept. 1970) (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Los Angeles Free Press IV:14 (31 Mar. 1967) (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - National Guardian XVIII:20 (19 Feb. 66) (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - New University Conference Newsletter I:1 (24 May 1968) (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - New University Conference Newsletter III:1 (15 Aug. 1969) (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - New York Review of Books 24 Sept. 1970 (Box 30, Folder 25)
      ('Fidel Castro: Has Cuba Failed?')
    - Peace and Freedom National Organizer (SF) 20 July 1968 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Phoenix (Nashville, TN) I:4 (Dec. 1968) (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Rag (Austin, TX) I:27, (17 July 1967) (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Rising Up Angry (Chicago) II:1 (Summer 1970) (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Rolling Stone 1970: 7, 19 March; 2 April (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - San Francisco Cream 2 June 1967 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - UWM Post (Madison, WI) VII:28 (12 Jan. 1968) (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Village Voice (Box 30, Folder 33)
      - 18 May 67, -damaged
      - 26 Oct. 67; 7 Dec. 67
      - 14 Dec. 67
    - Worker 11 Aug. 1964 (Box 30, Folder 31)
      (Washington Square rally)
- Series III: Serials
  These serial periodicals belonged to either JS or RS, although the researcher may determine the owner the from facts such as publish date or subject field. They are arranged alphabetically, and by date within each title.
  - 3 Continents, revue d'actualité du Tiers Monde Apr.-June 1967 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - AHA Newsletter Dec. 1969, Feb., April, June 1970 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Alabama Historical Quarterly Spring 1972 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - American Historical Review LXXV:2- 5, (1970) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - American Historical Review LXXV:7 (1970) (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - American Scholar Spring 1963, Aut. 1967 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Annals of the American Society for Political and Social Science Sept. 1956 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Buffalo Law Review 14:1 (Fall 1964) (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Black Scholar Dec. 1969 (2 copies), Jan. 72,, March 72, May 72, July 75 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin of the Institute for the Study of the History and Culture of the USSR (Munich) I:1-3, 5, 7, 8 (1954) (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin of the Institute for the Study of the History and Culture of the USSR (Munich) II:1- IV:3 (Jan. 1955-March 1957), [27 items] (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Bulletin of the Institute for the Study of the History and Culture of the USSR (Munich) IV:4- V:2 (1957-58);VIII:2, 5 (1961), [13 items] (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Civil War History. Cumulative index 1955-59, XII:4, XIII:1-XVI:2, XVII:1,2 (1966-71) (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - review of RS's book in XVII:2
  - Colby Library Quarterly Dec. 1974 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - article signed by author, Randall Miller, for the Starobins
  - Collegiate Challenge (Campus Crusade for Christ -"a new kind of revolution at Berkeley!") VI:1 (1967) (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Forum X:1 (Spr. 1967) (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Commentary Oct. 1963 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Commercial and Financial Chronicle 24 Sept., 1953 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Controversy (Cornell political magazine) I:1 (Dec. 1960) (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Dialogue I;1 (Nov. 1960) (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - L'Express 1965 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - F.A.S. Newsletter Jan. 1959 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Fact I:5 (Sept. 1964) (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - For a lasting peace, For a people's democracy! (Bucharest, Romania) 9/10/54 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Forum (Cornell) nos. 5,6 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Fourth International (Marxist Quarterly) Fall 54, Fall 55, Win. 55 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Georgia Historical Quarterly Sept. 65 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Harper's Magazine Sept. 67 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - cover article by William Styron: "The Confessions of Nat Turner"
  - L'Humanité Dimanche (France) 9/6/59 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - I.F. Stone's Weekly IV:39 (Oct. 56) (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - I.F. Stone's Bi-Weekly Sept. 63 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Illinois Business Review XVIII:1 (Jan. 1961) (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Industrial South VII:6 (1955) (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Interior Decorators' News II:22 (Sept. 1959) (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - International Free Trade Union News III:7 (July 1948) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - International Socialist Review Fall, Winter 1969 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Journal of American History LV:3, LVI:1-4 (1968-70) (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Lawyers Guild Review XVII:3 (Fall 1967) (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Liberation (1970 ed. marked) June 60, Aug. 69, Feb. 70 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Massachusetts Review X:3 (Summer 1969) (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Masses & Mainstream Oct. 1953 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Mainstream May 1960 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Mid-Century no. 24 (Apr. 1961) (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Mobilizer-to end mass murder in Vietnam I:2 (Feb, 1967) (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Modern Quarterly VII:2, 3 (1952); II:1, 3; III:6; X:3/4; XI:6; XII:8, 9; XIV:3/4, 6, 10 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Monthly Review XV:9, 11; XVI:1, 2, 3/ 4, 11, 12;XVII:1, 2; XIX:8;XX:2; XXI:6, [12 items] (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Monthly Review, [9 items] (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Movement (SF State, Robt. Starobin) Apr. 67, July 68 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Nation Sept. 57; June 61; Nov. 62; Dec. 64 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - New International XXII:3 (Fall 1956) (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - New Leader Jan. 1965 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - New Politics Fall 61, Winter 62 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - New Republic June 56; Apr. 57; Nov. 58; Sept. 59; Sept. 68 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    Sept. 68 marked "save for letters on Chicago Convention"
  - New South Student V:5-6, VI:1 (1968-9) (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - New York Guild Lawyer Sept. 1957 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - New University Thought Spr., Summer 61; Summer 64; Mar. 68 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Nouvel Observateur June 1965 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Oregon Democrat XXII:4, 6 (1954) (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Pacific Affairs XXII:3, 4 (1949); XXVII:3 (1954) (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Party Voice (NY State Communist Party) Jan., Nov., Dec. 1956; Jan. 1957, 1 w/o cover (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Problemas (Argentina) Sept. 1953 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Progressive June 1966 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Political Affairs Mar.1964, Mar. 1966 Quaker History Aut. 1972 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Radical America II:1,6; IV:2,3; V:2 (2 copies); VI:1 (1968-72) (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - RS's article: "Racism and the American Experience" in V:2
  - Radicals in the Professions Newsletter I:4 (Feb. 1968) (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Rights VII:1 (1960); X:4/5 (1963) (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Review of Radical Political Economics Aug. 1970 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Special Issue: "The War and its Impact on Our Economy"
  - Science and Society XVI:1-3 (1952) (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - SDS New Left Notes Oct. 1968; Mar. 1967; 26 Aug. 69 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Socialist Call XXV:10-11 (Oct.-Nov. 1957); XXVI:1 (Jan. 1958) (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Socialist Revolution I:1 (1970) (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Southern Patriot Jan. 56, Nov. 67, Mar. 68, Feb.75 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Survey no. 18 (Aug. 57); no. 23-25 (1958) (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Studies on the Left I:3; II:2 (2 copies); III:3,4; IV:1,3; V:1, 2, 4; VI:3; VII:1 (1960-67) (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Survey no. 54 (Jan. 1965) (Box 41, Folder 6)
    inner cover-note from JS to RS
  - Survey no. 56, 57, 69, 72, 76, 79 (July 1965-Spr. 71) (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Survey (Soviet Survey) no. 21-22 (Nov. 57) (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Tennessee Historical Quarterly Spr. 1974 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Time Feb. 1955 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    (Khrushchev)
  - Time Dec. 1956 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    (letters to ed. against Khrushchev as man of the year)
  - Trends and Tides (T&T) V:1; VI:1 (1949-50) (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - UAW Administrative Letter 17 Sept. 1957 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Viet Report Aug/Sept. 65, Nov./Dec., Jan. 66, Mar./Apr. 66 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - La Voix du Peuple (Belgian Communist weekly) June 1965 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - William and Mary Quarterly XXIV:1-4; XXV:1-3; XXVI:2 (1968-69) (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - William and Mary Quarterly XXVII:1-2; XXVIII:3;XXIX1-2; XXX:2-4; XXVII (1970-73) (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - William and Mary Quarterly XXV:4; XXVI:1,3-4, XXXI:1-2 (1968-74) (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - William and Mary Quarterly XXXI:3-4; XXXII:1 (1974-75) (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - World II:16 7/31/73 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - year one Oct. 1969 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Young Socialist Review Aug. 1961 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Zeit newspaper (Germany) 3/12/65 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Vietnamese magazines/newspapers 1953 (Box 47(OS), Folder 1)
    Laodong, D"c L(p, Gi...o Duc Nh(n D(n,Qu(n D"i Nh(n D(n
  - Canadian Magazine (Toronto Star) 7/5/65 (Box 47(OS), Folder 2)
  - Esquire 9/65 (Box 47(OS), Folder 3)
  - Look 4/16/57, 11/16/65 (Box 47(OS), Folder 4)